<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Henry McCarthy</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Henry McCarthy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:41:01 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Brochure Building: Toson Hulstai Nature Preserve</title>
      <link>/portfolio/work2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:41:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/work2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Fall 2017, I had the wonderful opportunity to study abroad in Mongolia. While living in the country&amp;rsquo;s capital, Ulaanbaatar, I worked as an intern for The Nature Conservancy. During my internship I created and updated GIS files, proofread conservation reports, and created a National Parks style brochure for TNC Mongolia&amp;rsquo;s anchor site.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Bagpiper&#39;s Guide to the US: Exploring Spatial and Gender Patterns in the Pipe Band Community</title>
      <link>/portfolio/work3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:44:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/work3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Under Construction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urban GIS: Northside Achievement Zone</title>
      <link>/portfolio/work4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:41:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/work4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most meaningful classes I&amp;rsquo;ve taken at Macalester is Urban GIS. The semester that I took Urban GIS our class partnered with the Northside Achievement Zone (NAZ) and produced a report to help inform decision-making and illustrate spatial trends in North Minneapolis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dengue Risk Assessment on the Island of Hawaii</title>
      <link>/portfolio/work5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:53:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/work5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Macalester College / Advanced Geospatial Analysis / Spring 2018&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Sentimental: An Analysis of Twin Cities Tweets and Headlines</title>
      <link>/portfolio/work7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 20:02:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/work7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a final project for my Intro to Data Science course I worked with four other students to analyze tweets and news headlines that mention Mayors Melvin Carter and Jacob Frey of St. Paul and Minneapolis, respectively. This was an exciting project that allowed me to expand my data wrangling and visualization skills using RStudio.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nature Conservancy - Grassland and Stream Surveys</title>
      <link>/portfolio/work6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:57:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/work6/</guid>
      <description>This past summer I had an exciting internship with The Nature Conservancy which allowed me to pursue my environmental and GIS interests while gaining valuable field experience.
Under Construction
Far far away, behind the word mountains, far from the countries Vokalia and Consonantia, there live the blind texts. Separated they live in Bookmarksgrove right at the coast of the Semantics, a large language ocean.
A small river named Duden flows by their place and supplies it with the necessary regelialia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brushing Up and Starting Fresh: Esri Story Maps, Adobe Animate, and Fire Ecology</title>
      <link>/portfolio/work8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:59:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/work8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my Advanced Cartography and Geovisualization class this past semester I was tasked with creating a dynamic visualization using a new or somewhat unfamiliar platform. Interested in learning about animation in Adobe, I decided to create a series of short animations to illustrate concepts in fire ecology (a field that I have long been curious about but have not studied in detail). Wanting to stay up to date with Esri Story Maps, I decided to use this as a platform to host my animations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doodles Revisited: Getting to Know the Wacom Intuos Graphics Tablet</title>
      <link>/portfolio/work9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:56:17 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/work9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a fun side project I&amp;rsquo;ve recently started working on as a way to learn how to use a Wacom graphics tablet. A few weeks ago I came across some of my childhood sketchbooks and had the idea to recreate them in Adobe Illustrator. I am a new owner of a graphics tablet and have been enjoying my time learning the tablet&amp;rsquo;s various capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defining a Style</title>
      <link>/portfolio/work10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 20:22:08 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/work10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was one of my favorite assignments from my Advanced Cartography and Geovisualization class last semester. We were instructed to create a style sheet for just about anything, so having a bit of experience creating my TNC Mongolia brochure I decided to further develop what I envisioned the National Parks &amp;ldquo;style&amp;rdquo; to be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freelance</title>
      <link>/portfolio/work11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 20:23:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/work11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In addition to class assignments and professional projects, I have done some work as a freelance cartographer and graphic designer for consultants, independent businesses, and professors. I am always happy to take on new projects so feel free to get in contact with me!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable Development Goals in Mongolia</title>
      <link>/portfolio/work12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 20:23:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/work12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While I was studying abroad in Mongolia I had the chance to complete a rapid-fire, three-day externship with a local non-profit called the Ger Community Mapping Center (GCMC). At GCMC I created an infographic highlighting UN Sustainable Development Goals as they pertain to Mongolia&amp;rsquo;s capital.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>